A Guide to the Selden Repass Papers, 1871-1928, Undated.
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Selden Repass Papers 1871-1928, Undated.
Special Collections, Kegley Library
2008.2
24 folders.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased in 2008.
Biographical Information
Selden W. L. Repass, the son of Gordon Repass and Anna M. Sharitz Repass, was born 22 August 1850. He married Elizabeth Florence Earheart in September 1875. They had one child, Olive Anna Repass who was born 25 March 1879. Florence died 16 June 1893. After Florence's death, Selden married Lula Mae Umberger, the daughter of Abraham Umberger and Elizabeth J. Marten, on 15 April 1897. She died on 11 November 1898 and was buried in Marvin Methodist Church Cemetery in Wythe County, as was Florence Repass.
Repass married his third wife, Ella B. Patterson, on 19 February 1901. He remained an active member of Marvin Methodist Church until his death on 3 June 1929. He is buried in Marvin Methodist Church Cemetery along with many members of his family.
Scope and Content
The Papers consist of correspondence and financial records issued and received by Selden W. Repass and his family.
Contents List
- Folder 1. Correspondence. 1874-1908, Undated., 6 items.
  This folder contains letters from Florence Earheart to her future husband Selden Repass; other correspondents include Robert E. Earhart, W. W. Hurt, and Humphreys-Davidson Hardware Company.
- Folder 2. Tax Receipts - Selden Repass. 1894-1909., 14 items.
  This folder contains tax tickets and receipts received by Selden Repass from the county of Wythe.
- Folder 3. Tax Receipts - Selden Repass. 1910-1928., 15 items.
  This folder contains tax tickets and receipts received by Selden Repass from the county of Wythe and State of Virginia.
- Folder 4. Tax Receipts - Ella G. Repass, Ella P. Repass, Olive Repass, Selden Repass. 1878-1928., 13 items.
  This folder contains tax tickets and receipts received by Ella G. Repass (sister of Selden Repass) dated 1878; receipts of Ella Patterson Repass (third wife of Selden Repass) dating from 1924 to 1928; receipts of Olive Repass (daughter of Selden Repass and Ella Patterson Repass) dating from 1926 to 1928. Also included in this folder are tickets and receipts of Selden Repass for dog taxes levied by the county of Wythe for the years 1903 to 1906.
- Folder 5. Receipts. 1871-1877., 8 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Reuben F. Repass, Anna M. Repass, Emily V. Repass, Selden Repass, William B. Foster, and Rufus Brown; all receipts pertain to the estates of William Repass, Gordon Repass, and Henry C. Earhart.
- Folder 6. Receipts. 1878-1879., 12 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, A. Umberger, R. C. Kent, J. L. Lindamood, Anna M. Repass, Ella G. Repass, William B. Foster, M. D. Brown, and Solomon Umberger; most of the receipts pertain to the settlement of the Gordon Repass estate.
- Folder 7. Receipts. 1880-1885., 15 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Henry C. Earheart, Cynthia J. Earheart, Robert C. Earheart, Rufus Brown, Polly Earhart, Luther D. Earhart, and D. A. St. Clair.
- Folder 8. Receipts. 1886-1889., 13 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Rufus Brown, J. M. Porter, Hattie M. Earhart, Wytheville Dispatch per F. H. Terry, R. C. Kent, James Y. Walker for Post Office, and Joseph A. Rider.
- Folder 9. Receipts. 1890-1894., 17 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Wytheville Dispatch per F. H. Terry, Florence Earheart Repass, Charles L. Baumgardner, W. W. Rich, Thomas Sult, Isaac King, W. E. Hillenberg, Foote & Johnson, Huffard and Brown, Loomis and Hart Manufacturing Company, Hartford Fire Insurance Company, and J. N. Phipps.
- Folder 10. Receipts. 1895-1896., 12 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Maryland Fertilizing and Manufacturing Company, M. D. Brown, G. W. Cline, M. Cassell, W. B. Cassell, C. R. Baumgardner, S. F. Ewald, Huffard & Brown, Marvin Church, Vernon Vernon, T. F. Joines, C. L. Jennings, and James G. Tinsley & Company.
- Folder 11. Receipts. 1897-1899., 18 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, W. M. Coley, T. H. R. Christie (piano dealer), W. E. Hillenberg, A. M. Repass, J. P. Copenhaver, M. D. Brown, Tarter Brothers, F. H. Terry of the Wytheville Dispatch, Rich Brothers, Buck & Peery, J. Stanger Brown, C. C. Catron, J. H. Marsteller, and E. M. Davis.
- Folder 12. Receipts. 1900-1901., 13 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Graham & Sayers, McCormick Harvesting Machine Company, Coley & Etter, Rural Retreat Telephone Service, E. M. Holston, Rebekah Moore, James H. Whisman, J. W. Menefee, Empire Drill Company, and William Dyer.
- Folder 13. Receipts. 1902-May 1903., 12 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, William Dyer, Rutner & Catron, Rural Retreat Telephone Company, D. S. Fox, Mrs. W. C. Buck, George D. Brown, Charles R. Pepper of the Times Printing Company, J. A. Cormany Blacksmith & Repair Work, and Humphreys-Davidson Hardware Company.
- Folder 14. Receipts. June - December 1903., 11 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Johnson & Blackwell, J. M. Poston, Heuser Brothers, Foote & Johnson, E. M. Davis, Robert D. Earhart, Buck & Peery, Alice Six, Wytheville Dispatch per Alex Forward, and William Dyer.
- Folder 15. Receipts. 1904-1905., 12 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, William Dyer of Martha Washington College, Humphreys-Davidson Hardware Company, Smith Manufacturing Company, S. F. Ewald Insurance Agency, Roanoke Carriage Company, and Rural Retreat Telephone Company.
- Folder 16. Receipts. 1906-1909., 5 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, The Delineator, Tarter Brothers, Wytheville Dispatch per J. Whitman, and the Rural Retreat Mutual Telephone Company.
- Folder 17. Receipts. 1910-1913., 13 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Children's Home Society of Virginia, Wytheville Dispatch per J. Whitman, Martha Washington College, Farmers Mutual Fire Association, Marion Female College, Farmers Supply Company, D. R. Doak of the Times Printing Company, Emory and Henry College, Barrick Publishing Company for the New York Packer, The Cincinnati Packer, The Chicago Packer, The Kansas City Packer, and The Pacific Coast Packer, and Dr. K. M. Ferguson.
- Folder 18. Receipts. 1914-1915., 11 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Children's Home Society, H. E. Sever, Dr. W. G. Delp, Southwest Virginia Enterprise per J. Whitman, Farmers' Mutual Fire Association, E. F. Neff General and Farm Trucking, The Roanoke Times, Farmers Supply Company, and Moore-Cottrell Subscription Agencies.
- Folder 19. Receipts. 1917-1919., 12 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Farmers' Mutual Fire Association, J. T. Wampler, Southern Planter Publishing Company, W. E. Schmidt Company, Southwest Virginia Enterprise by J. Whitman, Dr. W. G. Delph, the Anti-Saloon League of America, Blue Grass Hardware Company, Centenary Methodist Missions as member of Marvin Church, and Children's Home Society of Virginia.
- Folder 20. Receipts. 1920-1922., 14 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Methodist Missionary Centenary of Marvin Methodist Church, Southwest Virginia Enterprise by J. Whitman, Rural Retreat Mutual Telephone, and Joe K. Buck & Company General Merchandise.
- Folder 21. Receipts. 1923-1928., 14 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, Methodist Missionary Centenary of Marvin Methodist Church, Southwest Virginia Enterprise per J. Whitman, and E. C. Huffman, Children's Home Society of Virginia, The Roanoke Times, The Farm Journal, Roanoke College, Rural Retreat Mutual Telephone Company, and Harry Umberger.
- Folder 22. Receipts. Undated., 6 items.
  This folder contains receipts issued and received by Selden Repass, H. C. Earhart, Success Art Company, F. S. Blair, and Stowe Hauling Lumber Company of Bristol (bill for Black Lick School).
- Folder 23. Receipts and Miscellaneous - John M. Porter. 1886-1894., 11 items.
  Documents found in this folder include receipts, a deed, and other materials concerning John M. Porter and Selden Repass.
- Folder 24. Miscellaneous. 1902-1917., 7 items.
  This folder contains a check payable to Robert D. Earhart from S. W. Repass, deposit slip for Augsburg Bank, check to Stephen Umberger, membership certificate to Wythe County Livestock and Agricultural Society for Selden Repass, certificate for appointment of Selden Repass as trustee for Black Lick School District, page of account notes by Selden Repass, and page of accounts of Selden Repass with Marvin Church.